Finding Aid for Alexander G. Ruthven Papers
Bentley Historical Library
- President's Office, 1929-1952
  - Correspondence Files, 1929-1951
    - 1944-1945
      - Alumni Association (Box 37)
        (37-36)
      - American (Miscellaneous) (Box 37)
        (37-37)
      - American Council on Education (Box 37)
        (37-38)
      - Annuities (Box 37)
        (37-39)
      - Anonymous-Asylum (Box 37)
        (37-40)
      - Applications for Positions (Box 38)
        (38-1)
      - Associations, Bureaus, etc. (Box 38)
        (38-2)
      - Awards (Box 38)
        (38-3)
      - Ba-Be (Box 38)
        (38-4)
      - Babst, Earl D. (Box 38)
        (38-5)
      - Barbour Scholarships (Box 38)
        (38-6)
      - Bf-Br (Box 38)
        (38-7)
      - Blakeman, Edward W. (Box 38)
        (38-8)
      - Bs-Bz (Box 38)
        (38-9)
      - Ca-Ch (Box 38)
        (38-10)
      - Ci-Co (Box 38)
        (38-11)
      - Civil Service (Box 38)
        (38-12)
      - Clements Library (Box 38)
        (38-13)
      - Conklin Fund (Box 38)
        (38-14)
      - Cp-Cz (Box 38)
        (38-15)
      - Da-Di (Box 38)
        (38-16)
      - Dj-Dz (Box 38)
        (38-17)
      - Dormitories (Box 38)
        (38-18)
      - Ea-Ez (Box 38)
        (38-19)
      - Elliott, Eugene B. (Box 38)
        (38-20)
      - Extension Service (Box 38)
        (38-21)
      - Fa-Fq (Box 38)
        (38-22)
      - F.M. Radio (Box 38)
        (38-23)
      - Fr-Fz (Box 38)
        (38-24)
      - Fraternities (Box 38)
        (38-25)
      - Fresh Air Camp (Box 38)
        (38-26)
      - Ga-Gz (Box 38)
        (38-27)
      - Gale, Esson M. (Box 38)
        (38-28)
      - Gram, L.M. (Box 38)
        (38-29)
      - Ha-Hd (Box 38)
        (38-30)
      - He-Hz (Box 38)
        (38-31)
      - I (Box 38)
        (38-32)
      - J (Box 38)
        (38-33)
      - Ka-Kz (Box 38)
        (38-34)
      - Karpinski, Louis C. (Box 38)
        (38-35)
      - Kraus, Edward H. (Box 38)
        (38-36)
      - La-Lz (Box 38)
        (38-37)
      - Lawyers Club (Box 38)
        (38-38)
      - Literary College (Box 38)
        (38-39)
      - Ma-Mb (Box 39)
        (39-1)
      - Mc-Mh (Box 39)
        (39-2)
      - McClusky, Howard Y. (Box 39)
        (39-3)
      - Memberships (Box 39)
        (39-4)
      - Mexico, University of (Summer School) (Box 39)
        (39-5)
      - Mi-Mz (Box 39)
        (39-6)
      - Michigan (Box 39)
        (39-7)
      - Military Training (Box 39)
        (39-8)
      - Museum (Department of Anthropology) (Box 39)
        (39-9)
      - Na-Nz (Box 39)
        (39-10)
      - Naval R.O.T.C. (Box 39)
        (39-11)
      - O (Box 39)
        (39-12)
      - Pa-Pz (Box 39)
        (39-13)
      - Pollock (Salary Study) (Box 39)
        (39-14)
      - Qa-Qz (Box 39)
        (39-15)
      - Questionnaires (Box 39)
        (39-16)
      - Ra-Re (Box 39)
        (39-17)
      - Radio (Box 39)
        (39-18)
      - Regents-Alumni Scholarships (Box 39)
        (39-19)
      - Reorganization (Box 39)
        (39-20)
      - Rf-Rz (Box 39)
        (39-21)
      - Sa-Sh (Box 39)
        (39-22)
      - Scholarships, Prizes, etc. (Box 39)
        (39-23)
      - Si-Sz (Box 39)
        (39-24)
      - Smith, Shirley W. (Box 39)
        (39-25)
      - Stason, E. Blythe (Box 39)
        (39-26)
      - Stevenson, R.A. (Box 39)
        (39-27)
      - Student Religious Association (Box 39)
        (39-28)
      - Ta-Tz (Box 39)
        (39-29)
      - Thirteen (Committee of) (Box 39)
        (39-30)
      - Ua-Uz (Box 39)
        (39-31)
      - U.S. Departments (Box 39)
        (39-32)
      - U.S. Legislature (Box 39)
        (39-33)
      - University Hospital (Box 39)
        (39-34)
      - Va-Vz (Box 40)
        (40-1)
      - Visitors (Box 40)
        (40-2)
      - Wa-Wd (Box 40)
        (40-3)
      - We-Wi (Box 40)
        (40-4)
      - Wj-Wz (Box 40)
        (40-5)
      - X-Y-Z (Box 40)
        (40-6)
      - Yoakum, C.S. (Box 40)
        (40-7)
    - 1945-1946
      - Aa-Az (Box 40)
        (40-8)
      - Acknowledgments (Box 40)
        (40-9)
      - Adams, James P. (Box 40)
        (40-10)
      - Alumni Association (Box 40)
        (40-11)
      - American (Miscellaneous) (Box 40)
        (40-12)
      - American Council on Education (Box 40)
        (40-13)
      - American Council on Education (Box 40)
        (40-14)
      - Annuities (Box 40)
        (40-15)
      - Anonymous-Asylum (Box 40)
        (40-16)
      - Applications for Positions (Box 40)
        (40-17)
      - Associations, Bureaus, etc. (Box 40)
        (40-18)
      - Ba-Be (Box 40)
        (40-19)
      - Babst, Earl D. (Box 40)
        (40-20)
      - Barbour Scholarships (Box 40)
        (40-21)
      - Bf-Bz (Box 40)
        (40-22)
      - Blakeman, Edward W. (Box 40)
        (40-23)
      - Briggs, Robert P. (Box 40)
        (40-24)
      - Building Fund, 1945 (Box 40)
        (40-25)
      - Ca-Cn (Box 40)
        (40-26)
      - Clements Library (Box 40)
        (40-27)
      - Co-Cz (Box 40)
        (40-28)
      - Da-Di (Box 41)
        (41-1)
      - Dj-Dz (Box 41)
        (41-2)
      - Ea-Ez (Box 41)
        (41-3)
      - Elliott, Eugene B. (Box 41)
        (41-4)
      - Fa-Fz (Box 41)
        (41-5)
      - Fees (Box 41)
        (41-6)
      - Furstenberg, A.C. (Box 41)
        (41-7)
      - Ga-Gz (Box 41)
        (41-8)
      - Gale, Esson M. (Box 41)
        (41-9)
      - Griffith, R. Gordon (Box 41)
        (41-10)
      - Ha-He (Box 41)
        (41-11)
      - Hf-Hz (Box 41)
        (41-12)
      - Ia-Iz (Box 41)
        (41-13)
      - Intercollegiate Athletics (Board in Control of) (Box 41)
        (41-14)
      - I (Box 41)
        (41-15)
      - Ka-Kh (Box 41)
        (41-16)
      - Ki-Kz (Box 41)
        (41-17)
      - La-Li (Box 41)
        (41-18)
      - Lj-Lz (Box 41)
        (41-19)
      - Ma-Md (Box 41)
        (41-20)
      - McClusky, Howard Y. (Box 41)
        (41-21)
      - Me-Mz (Box 41)
        (41-22)
      - Memberships (Box 41)
        (41-23)
      - Military Training (Box 41)
        (41-24)
      - Museum of Art and Archaeology (Box 41)
        (41-25)
      - Na-Nz (Box 41)
        (41-26)
      - Naval R.O.T.C. (Box 41)
        (41-27)
      - Oa-Oz (Box 41)
        (41-28)
      - Osborn, Chase S. (Box 41)
        (41-29)
      - Pa-Ph (Box 41)
        (41-30)
      - Pi-Pz (Box 41)
        (41-31)
      - Plant Extension Committee (Box 41)
        (41-32)
      - Questionnaires (Box 41)
        (41-33)
      - Ra-Ri (Box 41)
        (41-34)
      - Regents-Alumni Scholarships (Box 41)
        (41-35)
      - Rj-Rz (Box 41)
        (41-36)
      - Sa-Sh (Box 42)
        (42-1)
      - Scholarships, Prizes, etc. (Box 42)
        (42-2)
      - Si-Sp (Box 42)
        (42-3)
      - Smith, Ira M. (Box 42)
        (42-4)
      - Sq-Sz (Box 42)
        (42-5)
      - Stason, E. Blythe (Box 42)
        (42-6)
      - Student Religious Association (Box 42)
        (42-7)
      - T (Box 42)
        (42-8)
      - Ua-Uz (Box 42)
        (42-9)
      - U.S. Departments (Box 42)
        (42-10)
      - U.S. Legislature (Box 42)
        (42-11)
      - U.S. Office of Education (Box 42)
        (42-12)
      - University Hospital (Box 42)
        (42-13)
      - Va-Vz (Box 42)
        (42-14)
      - Vaughan, Henry F. (Box 42)
        (42-15)
      - Victory Reunion (June "46") (Box 42)
        (42-16)
      - Visitors (Box 42)
        (42-17)
      - Wa-We (Box 42)
        (42-18)
      - Wf-Wz (Box 42)
        (42-19)
      - X-Y-Z (Box 42)
        (42-20)
      - Yoakum, Clarence S. (Box 42)
        (42-21)
    - 1946-1947
      - Aa-Az (Box 42)
        (42-22)
      - Acknowledgments (Box 42)
        (42-23)
      - Adams, James P. (Box 42)
        (42-24)
      - Airport Dedication (Box 42)
        (42-25)
      - Alumni Association (Box 42)
        (42-26)
      - Alumni Relations (Box 42)
        (42-27)
      - American (Miscellaneous) (Box 42)
        (42-28)
      - American Council on Education (Box 42)
        (42-29)
      - Anonymous-Asylum (Box 42)
        (42-30)
      - Applications for Positions (Box 42)
        (42-31)
      - Association of American Universities (Box 42)
        (42-32)
      - Associations, Bureaus, etc. (Box 42)
        (42-33)
      - Ba-Be (Box 43)
        (43-1)
      - Babst, Earl (Box 43)
        (43-2)
      - Barbour Scholarships (Box 43)
        (43-3)
      - Bf-Bz (Box 43)
        (43-4)
      - Biographical Sketches (Box 43)
        (43-5)
      - Bodenstab, John (Box 43)
        (43-6)
      - Briggs, Robert P. (Box 43)
        (43-7)
      - Blakeman, Edward W. (Box 43)
        (43-8)
      - Ca-Cl (Box 43)
        (43-9)
      - Citation, Regents (Box 43)
        (43-10)
      - Clements Library (Box 43)
        (43-11)
      - Cm-Cz (Box 43)
        (43-12)
      - Cooley Foundation (Box 43)
        (43-13)
      - Council of State College Presidents (Box 43)
        (43-14)
      - Da-Dz (Box 43)
        (43-15)
      - Dana, Samuel T. (Box 43)
        (43-16)
      - Deans (Box 43)
        (43-17)
      - Ea-Ez (Box 43)
        (43-18)
      - Economic Club of Detroit (Box 43)
        (43-19)
      - Elliott, Eugene B. (Box 43)
        (43-20)
      - Encyclopedias, Dictionaries, etc. (Box 43)
        (43-21)
      - Extension Service (Box 43)
        (43-22)
      - Fa-Fq (Box 43)
        (43-23)
      - Fr-Fz (Box 43)
        (43-24)
      - Ga-Gz (Box 43)
        (43-25)
      - Gale, Esson M. (Box 43)
        (43-26)
      - George, Colonel Edwin (Box 43)
        (43-27)
      - Griffith, R. Gordon (Box 43)
        (43-28)
      - Ha-Hd (Box 43)
        (43-29)
      - He-Hz (Box 43)
        (43-30)
      - Ia-Iz (Box 43)
        (43-31)
      - Intercollegiate Athletics (Board of) (Box 43)
        (43-32)
      - International Education (Committee on) (Box 43)
        (43-33)
      - J (Box 44)
        (44-1)
      - Ka-Kh (Box 44)
        (44-2)
      - Ki-Kz (Box 44)
        (44-3)
      - La-Lz (Box 44)
        (44-4)
      - Lawyers Club (Box 44)
        (44-5)
      - Ma-Md (Box 44)
        (44-6)
      - Me-Mz (Box 44)
        (44-7)
      - Memberships (Box 44)
        (44-8)
      - Michigan (Box 44)
        (44-9)
      - Na-Nz (Box 44)
        (44-10)
      - National (Box 44)
        (44-11)
      - Naval R.O.T.C. (Box 44)
        (44-12)
      - Niehuss, Marvin L. (Box 44)
        (44-13)
      - O (Box 44)
        (44-14)
      - Pa-Pn (Box 44)
        (44-15)
      - Po-Pz (Box 44)
        (44-16)
      - Perkins, John A. (Box 44)
        (44-17)
      - Plant Extension Committee (Box 44)
        (44-18)
      - Proposal No. 2 (Michigan Constitution) (Box 44)
        (44-19)
      - Qa-Qz (Box 44)
        (44-20)
      - Questionnaires (Box 44)
        (44-21)
      - Ra-Ri (Box 44)
        (44-22)
      - Residence Halls (Box 44)
        (44-23)
      - Rj-Rz (Box 44)
        (44-24)
      - Sa-Sd (Box 44)
        (44-25)
      - Scholarships, Prizes, etc- (Box 44)
        (44-26)
      - Se-Sn (Box 44)
        (44-27)
      - Smith, Ira M. (Box 44)
        (44-28)
      - So-Sz (Box 44)
        (44-29)
      - Student Religious Association (Box 44)
        (44-30)
      - Ta-Tz (Box 44)
        (44-31)
      - Thirteen, Committee of (Box 44)
        (44-32)
      - Ua-Uz (Box 44)
        (44-33)
      - U.S. Departments (Box 44)
        (44-34)
      - U.S. Legislature (Box 44)
        (44-35)
      - Va-Vz (Box 45)
        (45-1)
      - Visitors (Box 45)
        (45-2)
      - Wa-We (Box 45)
        (45-3)
      - Wf-Wz (Box 45)
        (45-4)
      - X-Y-Z (Box 45)
        (45-5)
    - 1947-1948
      - Aa-Az (Box 45)
        (45-6)
      - Adams, James P. (Box 45)
        (45-7)
      - Alumni Association (Box 45)
        (45-8)
      - Alumni Relations (Box 45)
        (45-9)
      - American (Miscellaneous) (Box 45)
        (45-10)
      - American Council on Education (Box 45)
        (45-11)
      - Applications for Positions (Box 45)
        (45-12)
      - Ba-Bd (Box 45)
        (45-13)
      - Be-Bq (Box 45)
        (45-14)
      - Br-Bz (Box 45)
        (45-15)
      - Ca-Ck (Box 45)
        (45-16)
      - Cl-Cz (Box 45)
        (45-17)
      - Commencement (Box 45)
        (45-18)
      - Da-Dz (Box 45)
        (45-19)
      - Dutch Celebration (Box 45)
        (45-20)
      - Ea-Ez (Box 45)
        (45-21)
      - Economic Club of Detroit (Box 45)
        (45-22)
      - Fa-Fz (Box 45)
        (45-23)
      - Fellowships, Prizes, etc. (Box 45)
        (45-24)
      - Foreign Student Aid (Box 45)
        (45-25)
      - Ga-Gz (Box 45)
        (45-26)
      - Gale, Esson M. (Box 45)
        (45-27)
      - Ha-He (Box 45)
        (45-28)
      - Hf-Hz (Box 45)
        (45-29)
      - Ia-Iz (Box 45)
        (45-30)
      - Intercollegiate Athletics (Box 45)
        (45-31)
      - J (Box 45)
        (45-32)
      - Ka-Kh (Box 46)
        (46-1)
      - Ki-Kz (Box 46)
        (46-2)
      - La-Lz (Box 46)
        (46-3)
      - Labor (Box 46)
        (46-4)
      - Ma-Mh (Box 46)
        (46-5)
      - Memberships (Box 46)
        (46-6)
      - Mi-Mz (Box 46)
        (46-7)
      - Na-Nz (Box 46)
        (46-8)
      - National (Box 46)
        (46-9)
      - Naval R.O.T.C. (Box 46)
        (46-10)
      - O (Box 46)
        (46-11)
      - P (Box 46)
        (46-12)
      - Q (Box 46)
        (46-13)
      - Questionnaires (Box 46)
        (46-14)
      - Ra-Rz (Box 46)
        (46-15)
      - Radio (Box 46)
        (46-16)
      - Rose Bowl (Box 46)
        (46-17)
      - Sa-Sj (Box 46)
        (46-18)
      - Sk-Sz (Box 46)
        (46-19)
      - T (Box 46)
        (46-20)
      - U-V (Box 46)
        (46-21)
      - Visitors (Box 46)
        (46-22)
      - W (Box 46)
        (46-23)
      - X-Y-Z (Box 46)
        (46-24)
    - 1948-1949
      - Aa-Am. (Box 46)
        (46-25)
      - American (Box 46)
        (46-26)
      - An-Az (Box 46)
        (46-27)
      - Applications for Positions (Box 46)
        (46-28)
      - Association of American Universities (Box 46)
        (46-29)
      - Ba-Bn (Box 46)
        (46-30)
      - Blakeman, Edward W. (Box 46)
        (46-31)
      - Bo-Bz (Box 46)
        (46-32)
      - Ca-Ck (Box 46)
        (46-33)
      - Cl-Cz (Box 46)
        (46-34)
      - D (Box 46)
        (46-35)
      - E (Box 47)
        (47-1)
      - Fa-Fz (Box 47)
        (47-2)
      - Fellowships, Prizes, etc. (Box 47)
        (47-3)
      - Ferris Institute (Box 47)
        (47-4)
      - G (Box 47)
        (47-5)
      - H (Box 47)
        (47-6)
      - I (Box 47)
        (47-7)
      - Intercollegiate Athletics (Board) (Box 47)
        (47-8)
      - I (Box 47)
        (47-9)
      - K (Box 47)
        (47-10)
      - L (Box 47)
        (47-11)
      - Ma-Mz (Box 47)
        (47-12)
      - Memberships (Box 47)
        (47-13)
      - Michigan (Box 47)
        (47-14)
      - Montague, Gilbert H. (Box 47)
        (47-15)
      - Na-Na (Box 47)
        (47-16)
      - Naval R.O.T.C. (Box 47)
        (47-17)
      - O (Box 47)
        (47-18)
      - P (Box 47)
        (47-19)
      - Q (Box 47)
        (47-20)
      - Questionnaires (Box 47)
        (47-21)
      - Ra-Rz (Box 47)
        (47-22)
      - R.O.T.C. (Box 47)
        (47-23)
      - Sa-Sj (Box 47)
        (47-24)
      - Sk-Sz (Box 47)
        (47-25)
      - T (Box 47)
        (47-26)
      - U (Box 47)
        (47-27)
      - V (Box 47)
        (47-28)
      - Visitors (Box 47)
        (47-29)
      - Wa-Wh (Box 47)
        (47-30)
      - Wi-Wz (Box 47)
        (47-31)
      - X-Y-Z (Box 47)
        (47-32)
    - 1949-1950
      - Aa-Az (Box 47)
        (47-33)
      - American Council on Education (Box 47)
        (47-34)
      - Anonymous-Asylum (Box 47)
        (47-35)
      - Applications for Positions (Box 47)
        (47-36)
      - Association of American Universities (Box 47)
        (47-37)
      - Ba-Bn (Box 48)
        (48-1)
      - Bo-Bz (Box 48)
        (48-2)
      - Ca-Cn (Box 48)
        (48-3)
      - Chinese Student Aid (Box 48)
        (48-4)
      - Co-Cz (Box 48)
        (48-5)
      - D (Box 48)
        (48-6)
      - E (Box 48)
        (48-7)
      - Fa-Fz (Box 48)
        (48-8)
      - Fellowships, Prizes, etc. (Box 48)
        (48-9)
      - Foreign Student Aid (Box 48)
        (48-10)
      - Ga-Gh (Box 48)
        (48-11)
      - Gi-Gz (Box 48)
        (48-12)
      - H (Box 48)
        (48-13)
      - I (Box 48)
        (48-14)
      - Intercollegiate Athletics (Board) (Box 48)
        (48-15)
      - J (Box 48)
        (48-16)
      - K (Box 48)
        (48-17)
      - L (Box 48)
        (48-18)
      - Ma-Mh (Box 48)
        (48-19)
      - Memberships (Box 48)
        (48-20)
      - Mi-Mz (Box 48)
        (48-21)
      - Michigan (Box 48)
        (48-22)
      - Na-Nz (Box 48)
        (48-23)
      - Naval R.O.T.C. (Box 48)
        (48-24)
      - O (Box 48)
        (48-25)
      - P (Box 48)
        (48-26)
      - Questionnaires (Box 48)
        (48-27)
      - Ra-Rz (Box 48)
        (48-28)
      - R.O.T.C. (Box 48)
        (48-29)
      - Sa-Sn (Box 48)
        (48-30)
      - Selective Service (Box 48)
        (48-31)
      - So-Sz (Box 48)
        (48-32)
      - T (Box 49)
        (49-1)
      - Thurston, Lee M. (Box 49)
        (49-2)
      - U (Box 49)
        (49-3)
      - V (Box 49)
        (49-4)
      - Visitors (Box 49)
        (49-5)
      - Wa-We (Box 49)
        (49-6)
      - Wf-Wz (Box 49)
        (49-7)
      - X-Y-Z (Box 49)
        (49-8)
    - 1950-1951
      - Aa-Az (Box 49)
        (49-9)
      - Applications for Positions (Box 49)
        (49-10)
      - Association of American Universities (Box 49)
        (49-11)
      - Ba-Bh (Box 49)
        (49-12)
      - Bi-Bz (Box 49)
        (49-13)
      - Bromberg, J. Edward (Box 49)
        (49-14)
      - Ca-Ci (Box 49)
        (49-15)
      - Ci-Cz (Box 49)
        (49-16)
      - Clements Library (Box 49)
        (49-17)
      - D (Box 49)
        (49-18)
      - E (Box 49)
        (49-19)
      - Fa-Fz (Box 49)
        (49-20)
      - Fellowships, Prizes, etc. (Box 49)
        (49-21)
      - Ford Foundation (Box 49)
        (49-22)
      - Foreign Students (Box 49)
        (49-23)
      - Fraternities (Discrimination) (Box 49)
        (49-24)
      - Ga-Gz (Box 49)
        (49-25)
      - Governing Boards (Conference of) (Box 49)
        (49-26)
      - Ha-Hz (Box 49)
        (49-27)
      - Hayward, Ralph (Box 49)
        (49-28)
      - Ia-Iz (Box 49)
        (49-29)
      - Intercollegiate Athletics (Board) (Box 49)
        (49-30)
      - International Education (Institute of) (Box 49)
        (49-31)
      - J (Box 49)
        (49-32)
      - K (Box 49)
        (49-33)
      - L (Box 50)
        (50-1)
      - Ma-Mh (Box 50)
        (50-2)
      - Memberships (Box 50)
        (50-3)
      - Mi-Mz (Box 50)
        (50-4)
      - Na-Nz (Box 50)
        (50-5)
      - National (Miscellaneous) (Box 50)
        (50-6)
      - Naval R.O.T.C. (Box 50)
        (50-7)
      - O (Box 50)
        (50-8)
      - Pa-Pe (Box 50)
        (50-9)
      - Pf-Pz (Box 50)
        (50-10)
      - Pollock-Political Science (Box 50)
        (50-11)
      - Questionnaires (Box 50)
        (50-12)
      - Ra-Rz (Box 50)
        (50-13)
      - Rose Bowl (Box 50)
        (50-14)
      - R.O.T.C. (Box 50)
        (50-15)
      - Sa-Sh (Box 50)
        (50-16)
      - Si-So (Box 50)
        (50-17)
      - Sp-Sz (Box 50)
        (50-18)
      - Ta-Tz (Box 50)
        (50-19)
      - Television (Box 50)
        (50-20)
      - Ua-Uz (Box 50)
        (50-21)
      - U.S. Navy-Letters of Consent (Box 50)
        (50-22)
      - Va-Vz (Box 50)
        (50-23)
      - Vaughn, Henry F. (Box 50)
        (50-24)
      - Visitors (Box 50)
        (50-25)
      - Wa-Wz (Box 50)
        (50-26)
      - Williams, Robert L. (Box 50)
        (50-27)
      - X-Y-Z (Box 50)
        (50-28)
    - Index file to selective correspondence (Box 66)
  - Subject Files, 1929-1952
    The second series within the President's Office subgroup is comprised of different subject files usually covering a period of more than one academic year. These files, which were separately maintained from the annual files, document the university's budget and relationship with the legislature; disciplinary and tenure cases; speeches given by Ruthven as president; correspondence with members of the board of regents; and various other university-related topics.
    - (State) Adult Education Program, 1944-1947 (Box 53)
      (53-11)
    - Alumni University, 1927-1929 (Box 53)
      (53-12)
    - American Association for Adult Education, 1943-1944 (Box 53)
      (53-13)
    - Athletic Conference, 1927 (Box 53)
      (53-14)
    - Awards, citations (Box 53)
      (53-15)
    - Conference of Five (Regents), 1921-1924 (Box 53)
      (53-16)
    - Foreign Exchange Students, 1943-1949 (Box 53)
      (53-17)
    - University of Heidelberg, 550th Anniversary, 1936 (Box 53)
      (criticism of U-M sending representative)
      (53-18)
    - North Central Questionnaire, 1935-1936 (Box 53)
      (53-19)
    - Schurtz, Shelby B., 1928-1939 (Box 53)
      (53-20)
    - Spill, William A., 1929-1939 (Box 53)
      (53-21)
    - Walker (Bryant) estate, 1936-1941 (Box 53)
      (53-21a)
    - Medical School Papers, 1945-1947 (Box 53)
      (53-22)
    - Medical School Papers, 1944-1947 (Box 53)
      (53-23)
    - Budget and legislative files, 1901-1948 (Box 55)
      (correspondence, reports, and committee minutes)
    - Budget and legislative files, 1948-1950 (Box 56)
    - National Association of State Universities files, 1941-1947 (Box 56)
    - National Association of State Universities files, 1947-1957 (Box 57)
    - National Association of State Universities files, Land Grant College Association files, State University Association files, 1947-1961 (Box 57)
      (combined files)
    - Discipline, tenure, and freedom of speech cases
      - Expulsion cases, 1940 (Box 58)
        (58-1)
      - Expulsion cases, 1940 (Box 58)
        (58-2)
      - Expulsion cases, 1940 (Box 58)
        (58-3)
      - McPhaul Case, 1952 (Box 58)
        (58-4)
      - Eisler-Marzani Case, 1947 (Box 58)
        (58-5)
      - American Youth for Democracy and Michigan Youth for Democratic Action, 1947 (Box 58)
        (58-6)
      - Pro-war sentiment of University of Michigan Faculty, 1940 (Box 58)
        (58-7)
      - National Student League, Strachey, Peace Meeting, 1936 (Box 58)
        (58-8)
      - McPhaul Case-Testimony, 1952 (Box 58)
        (58-9)
      - Discipline of Michigan Daily and American Student Union, 1940-1941 (Box 58)
        (58-10)
      - Dismissed students correspondence, 1940-1941 (Box 58)
        (58-11)
      - Dismissed students correspondence, 1940-1941 (Box 58)
        (58-12)
      - Dismissed students miscellaneous papers about, 1935-1936 (Box 58)
        (58-13)
      - Student Organizations, 1951-1952 (Box 58)
        (58-14)
      - Dismissal of C.N. Wenger and Carl Dahlstrom, 1943-1944 (Box 58)
      - Dismissal of C.N. Wenger and Carl Dahlstrom, 1943-1944 (Box 59)
    - Workers Educational Service, 1947-1949 (Box 59)
    - Workers Educational Service history, undated; 4 folders (Box 60)
    - Speeches as president (various topics), 1929-1951 (Box 60)
    - Speeches as president (various topics), 1929-1951 (Box 61)
      (continued)
    - Death Notices, Programs, Greetings, and Administrative Changes, 1929-1951 (Box 62)
    - Services, Memorials, Dedications, Gifts, Dinner Remarks, 1929-1951 (Box 62)
    - Commencement Addresses, 1930-1951
      - 1930-1939 (Box 63)
      - 1940-1951 (Box 63)
    - Greetings, 1929-1951 (Box 63)
    - Miscellaneous Speeches
      - 1929-1943 (Box 63)
      - 1944-1951 (Box 64)
  - Photographs